

Claudio Laas

Contact

Address: Haynstraße 29

20249 Hamburg

Phone: +569 40250776, 040 / 472027

Email: claudiolaas@gmail.com

Skill Highlight

- Strong interdisciplinary communication
- Experienced as a trainer
- Complex problem solver
- Automation-focus

Programming

Python: intermediate/advanced

SQL: intermediate/advanced

VBA: advanced

MS Office: advanced

Linux: basic R: basic

HTML/CSS: basic

Tableau: basic

Languages

German: native
English: fluent
Spanish: fluent

Out of Office

I am a livelong martial artist (Thaiboxing, Brazilian Jiu Jitsu) with a few tournaments under my belt and I enjoy cooking and spending time with friends.

Summary

I am a passionate Business Analyst specialized on data processing, automation and reporting. With more than two years of experience working with a large investment bank, I provide the compliance team with daily insights about suspicious account patterns and money movements. As a confident communicator I present information in a way that is clear and efficient. I am well versed in deep learning methodologies and concepts in Python and continuously advance my game through self-study and exchange with peers. I am excited to create solutions that make a positive impact on the lives of other people.

Experience

Business Analyst

2017-03 - current

Evalueserve Chile, Viña Del Mar, Chile

- Building ETL automations including Dashboards, Database connections and business logic implemented in Python
- Writing and maintaining SQL queries for Ad-Hoc requests and recurring processes (IBM, Teradata, Oracle, SQLite)
- Accelerated bi-monthly data manipulation task from a week to 40 minutes by automation via Python script
- Working as a Trainer for Python and VBA (Matplotlib, Pandas, Numpy, SQLite, Advanced Macros, Reporting with VBA)
- Participation in a Study Group for Machine Learning (In-depth presentations on Gradient Descent with relation to deep neural networks)

Working Student

2015-11 - 2016-03

Airbus Hamburg, Hamburg

- Data maintenance in SAP R/3
- Quality Management

Working Student

2014-12 - 2015-03

Lufthansa Technik AG, Hamburg

- Data maintenance in SAP R/3
- Responsibility for project documents

Working Student

2013-02 - 2014-10

Witzenmann Hamburg GmbH, Hamburg

- Restructuring of the Company (introduction of the
- 5S-Method of working)
- Workout and implementation of a Kanban-Control-System for logistical processes

Education

B.Sc. Mechanical Engineering

2011-11 - 2015-10

Technical University Hamburg – Hamburg

 Thesis: "Investigation of Influences of Vibration on Structure and Mechanical Properties of Complex, Bio-Inspired Composite Sediments" Grade: 1.7

High School Diploma

2000-06 - 2011-06

Gymnasium Corveystraße – Hamburg